<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-11T17:24:04-05:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CHAOS IN DIVIDE</title><subtitle>In Entropy, Find Peace.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - Tweaks &amp;amp; Fun</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - Tweaks &amp; Fun" /><published>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/folk-heroes-fun</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/10">&lt;p&gt;Very excited about the progress made thusfar, I’ve been really obsessing over Folk Heroes lately. Not that that’s bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This weekend I took it a little easier, mostly cleaning up some architectural messiness and restructuring some stuff so it doesn’t haunt me later. Programming is like gardening, weeds can be tolerated for a short time, but must be pruned before its too late!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit more exciting than refactoring are some tweaks I’ve done to the combat system. Previously, a mouseclick was… just that. A single event in the InputHandler that would result in Item Effects popping off. That’s not very exciting. A lot of action-RPG-type games have great features like power attacks and combos–I wanted to get in on that fun! So I altered my Item system to sometimes account for holding vs tapping. For example…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/taporhold.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;The slow rockets are from a mouse tap, while the speedy rockets are from holding down the fire button!&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun to animate the little red-glow and squash effect, and I’m really happy with how this new implementation is functioning within the existing systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also changed the old punch combo’s 3rd hook to be optional: if the player is holding the mouse (either in general, or specifically for the 3rd punch) they will do a higher-damage right hook attack. If they are tapping the mouse, the 3rd punch will instead be a quick left jab. I’m experimenting with different means of slowing the character during attacks and wind-ups, to give the combat a bit more weight than it currently has. Exciting times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/ponchhold.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;Still working on the sprite masking but, that may be polish of the very final stages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I am experimenting with all the different ways this can affect gameplay! From the rocket’s increased speed to the punch’s increased damage, there are a plethora of other possibilites such as: additional Effects, alteration of existing Effects, alternate animations/effects–endless possibilities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/hammerhold.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;Smashing rocks is now not as easy as a mouseclick... now... you have to hold it.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">Very excited about the progress made thusfar, I’ve been really obsessing over Folk Heroes lately. Not that that’s bad!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogpic.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - Farming &amp;amp; Growing</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/06" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - Farming &amp; Growing" /><published>2019-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/folk-heroes-farming</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/06">&lt;p&gt;Something new is growing…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s some cauliflower–I have successfully implemented farming and the day cycle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/plants.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;Not the prettiest pixel cauliflower in existence... but it'll do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing planting and growing was actually quite a bit easier than I anticipated! I had already created a system for targeting Tiles, and a system that linked Tiles to their contained WorldObject (what I am now calling objects like rocks, trees, flowers, etc. that are bound to a Tile location)… so now I just needed to connect the two! I created a WorldObjectSpawnEffect that targets Tiles… then, if the target Tile contains no WorldObject, instantiate a WorldObject and update the Tile to reflect its new inhabitant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next was time–plants need a lot of it! In the above GIF you can see that I had already set up a “Pass Day” function when I first implemented plants. All it did was issue a DayChange event, and each plant WorldObject had a component listening to that event. I created a WorldTileEffect that would change the soil into a watered soil sprite, and also update a new WaterLevel component of the Tile. If the plant’s Tile’s WaterLevel is satisfactory, the plant grows in response to a DayChange event. Otherwise, it tallies a “stagnantDays” integer. Enough stagnant days and the plant can die!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was implementing a day and night cycle. Now, traditional farming simulators usually have you go to sleep to pass a day (and save), and I plan to do the same! But first, minutes and hours needed to pass. Unity has a number of ways of incrementing values over time, I simply went with a ‘increment every X frames’ type of function to increment the time. Then I converted this raw integer into minutes and hours with some functions to determine AM/PM and the reset of the day, etc. Using some Unity AnimationCurves as well as Gradients, it was easy to set up a cycling color and intensity gradient for the sun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/daycycle.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;Time is racing! And the days are resetting at midnight. Just for demonstration ;-)&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very excited with how this ended up, and how all the pieces are already coming together! With this, I have completed the core farming loop of farming simulator games. But, there is still much more to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/mainloop.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img text-line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">Something new is growing…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogcrop.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - GUNS!</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/03" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - GUNS!" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/folk-heroes-guns</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/11/03">&lt;p&gt;Things are starting to get more interesting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve yet to play a farming simulator with very fleshed out combat. Stardew has the mine and the monster farm, but the combat is a little… unexciting. Well, nothing spices things up like a rocket launcher, right?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/rokkits.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;For this gif, the rockets are utilizing a tile-based targeting, which I didn't love--more on that in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/29&quot;&gt;my last post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing ranged attacks was a little interesting. I had already setup an animation-based system for attacks and the instantiation of Effects based on the item used. But each of those Effects was taking place at the target point of the player’s mouseclick! Now I had a new form of implementation: creating a moving Projectile object whose Effects would take place only when the object collided with something (or reached its end-of-life).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, instantiating the Projectile, giving it its starting rotation and velocity, etc. were all things I was pretty familiar with from my last foray into Folk Heroes (as well as another, much earlier game project I haven’t really gone into on my site, BLOKK THE BRAVE). I decided to make a ProjectileSpawnEffect class that inherited from Effect. When a item fires off its Effects, I wanted to leave the possibility for a Projectile-spawning item to do effects at its own location (for example, a magic effect that both fires a laser at a target and emits a shockwave from the user). This makes it easy to simply mix in ProjectileSpawnEffects into the list of an item’s Effects–and even different Projectiles can be fired from one use!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty pleased with how it turned out! Also had a lot of fun making the sprites for the muzzle flashes/explosions. I really don’t mention it enough, but pixel art is a whole lot of fun!! Animating especially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/gunsblood.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;I also started experimenting with Unity's Particle Emitter component and created this very Tarantino-esque blood splatter. Kickass!&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next? Toning down the violence and returning to a bit of farming: planting and growing!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">Things are starting to get more interesting…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/bloggun.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - Chopping &amp;amp; Smashing</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/29" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - Chopping &amp; Smashing" /><published>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/chopping-and-smashing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/29">&lt;p&gt;Chop it down, smash it! Bring it all down!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In games like Stardew, tilling and planting seeds is crucially important. But where can you plant your seeds if your farm is overgrown with weeds, trees, and miraculously-regenerating rocks?! After figuring out tilling the soil, I knew the next thing I needed to do was the destruction of these pesky natural obstructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The functionality was quite similar to my initial combat setup. Despite each object being confined to a single tile, after some testing I knew that I wanted the targeting of these objects to happen based on world-space collisions. Sure, it wouldn’t be pixel perfect, but it would be more real-feeling than a grid-based destruction! I realized at this point that different effects were going to target different things: tiles, their contained objects, or world-space objects like enemies/NPCs! That’s a lot of differing options, so I went ahead and created an abstract TargetingSolution class. Its two primary children are TileTargetingSolution and EntityTargetingSolution, the former selecting Tiles based on grid positions, and the latter selecting Unity GameObjects based on their world space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then needed to set up different WorldObject targeting parameters, like if it’s an enemy or a harvestable object, and of what type in these categories. What I currently have could probably use some restructuring to be a little cleaner, but hey–it works!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/chopping.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;I still need to create an axe sprite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure what I’ll be working on next, there’s still very much to do…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">Chop it down, smash it! Bring it all down!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogchop.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - Tile Modification</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - Tile Modification" /><published>2019-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/folk-heroes-tilling</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/26">&lt;p&gt;A major aspect of farming simulators like Stardew Valley and Harvest Moon is the farming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piggybacking on my targeting implementation from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/21&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, I realized I was going to need a means of converting from world space (in which the target point is found) to grid space. I was utilizing Unity’s Tilemap system for the grid placement, so I created a GridManager object that reads through the entire bounds of the Tilemap and holds onto a list of each Tile, its contents, etc. I could then input any point in world space and have the corresponding Tile (or its child objects) be returned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I needed to utilize Unity’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Unity-Technologies/2d-extras&quot;&gt;2D Extras&lt;/a&gt; repository, specifically the RuleTile script. This script allows for a Tile that adjusts its appearance based on adjacent Tiles. Using this, it became easy to create versatile Tilesets for a variety of layers and situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this was done, it was as easy as changing the effect of the Hoe item to not target any collisions, but instead to target the Tile inhabiting the target point. Then, if that Tile is of the correct identity (in this case, “Untilled Dirt”), the Hoe simply changes that “legalBeforeTile” to a corresponding “afterTile” (in this case, “Tilled Dirt”), all connected using the Unity Editor. Now, it’s easy to till and untill the soil!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/tilling.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;quotes text-line&quot;&gt;And as you can see, it is unable to till the grass/dirt border tiles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still considering other uses of this implementation for gameplay, but for now it’s exciting to have one of the most fundamental aspects of farming in the game! Up next: grid placement of objects like trees, rocks, etc. and how to interact with them!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">A major aspect of farming simulators like Stardew Valley and Harvest Moon is the farming!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogtill.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes - Initial Aiming and Combat</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/21" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes - Initial Aiming and Combat" /><published>2019-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/folk-heroes-combat</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/21">&lt;p&gt;Off to a good start! The basic combat functionality has been implemented.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is inspired by games like Enter the Gungeon, albeit with a minor twist. I wanted the player to be able to attack in a full 360 degrees (which works a little differently in 2.5D space!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, a Ray is shot from the camera and the point of intersection between the Ray and the Ground is recorded. I then use that position to calculate a “vector angle” (for example, “1,0 = right” or “0,1 = up”) from the player’s position towards that point of intersection. The player’s hands exist in a parent object that rotates to face in the direction of that angle. This allows me to reuse the same sprites for attacks in any angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took some noodling with the sprite alignments and Z-sorting, and some of that stuff is still being tweaked as you can see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/ponchin.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img text-line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really expect I’ll put the very precise level of polish required to clean up some the sprite sorting in very soon. For now, the functionality is my focus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After calculating the rotation of the hands’ parent object, that vector angle has its magnitude clamped based on the range of the player’s attack (a punch shouldn’t reach as far as a gun, of course), and a new point on the Ground is calculated. Right now, I simply instantiate a collision event at that point and see what enemies are inside. My goal is to later include targeting for various target types, including the tiles on the ground!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">Off to a good start! The basic combat functionality has been implemented.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogpunch.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Folk Heroes, Redux</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folk Heroes, Redux" /><published>2019-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/folk-heroes-redux</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/10/16">&lt;p&gt;After taking some time away from game development (and this website, and programming in general…) I decided it had been long enough! 
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I began brainstorming: “what’s a project that would get me really excited about programming again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there’s really one answer: games!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I looked back through the folder of in-progress game projects (it’s bigger than the two games I’m actually willing to share on this site!) and decided to revive my last project: “Folk Heroes!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/newlook.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;blog-img text-line&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to do some things differently, including the focus of the game’s mechanics and story. I wanted to draw inspiration from games like Stardew Valley to create a farming simulator-type game, but I want Folk Heroes to be different in its challenge and combative edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off by redesigning how I wanted to approach graphics. In my first instance of the project, I found a diffuse sprite shader online and just slapped it in. Instead, this time I focused on creating my own sprite shader that could utilize both diffuse shading and outlines! I had never really dabbled in shader code before, but it was fun and I love the result!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>vidya</name></author><summary type="html">After taking some time away from game development (and this website, and programming in general…) I decided it had been long enough!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.chaosindivide.com/assets/images/heroes/blogpic.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">cycl_c think_ng</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/09/15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="cycl_c think_ng" /><published>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/09/cyclic-thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/09/15">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/673051742&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little bit different with this one. It’s a little sadder, the vibe is a little bit more somber. The end utilizes a sample of $UICIDEBOY$ “Runnin’ Thru the 7th with my Woadies”. It was a fun one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>seizer</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">move のりこ</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/08/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="move のりこ" /><published>2019-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/08/move-noriko</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/08/12">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/663603116&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A phonky, trappy jam utilizing a sample of “My Life” my Noriko Miyamoto and Future’s “Move That Dope”. Really pleased with how this one came out, bass really bumps!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>seizer</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3AM in Ventura</title><link href="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/06/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3AM in Ventura" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/06/3am-in-ventura</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.chaosindivide.com/blog/2019/06/24">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/641570706&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, just like before, it seems I don’t use my blog that often, but I was excited about this tune. Maybe it’ll encourage me to do some more in the future?!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>seizer</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>